vacationhomerentals.com 2018-08-17

# TripAdvisor Vacation Rentals

Thank you for using the services of "TripAdvisor Vacation Rentals", a term we use to refer to any one of the three companies within the TripAdvisor group that provides an online platform and various tools to enable property owners or managers ("Owners") to list rental properties, and travelers to communicate with Owners and book such properties. These services may be accessed from any of the following websites and their related domains (referred to collectively here as the "Sites"): flipkey.com, holidaylettings.co.uk, housetrip.com, niumba.com, tripadvisor.com and vacationhomerentals.com.

In using our services, you will be subject to one or more of the Privacy Policies that are accessible from this page. Please read this introductory section to understand which of the policies applies to you.

  * If you are using any of the TripAdvisor websites (tripadvisor.com and related domains) to access our services, then TripAdvisor's _[Privacy Policy](https://www.tripadvisor.co.uk/pages/privacy.html)_ will apply to you.
  * The _Privacy Policy_ of FlipKey Inc. will apply if you use the FlipKey website or vacationhomerentals.com, or if you use any of the Sites to make a booking enquiry or request in relation to a property that is advertised by an Owner contracting with FlipKey Inc.
  * The _Privacy Policy_ of Holiday Lettings Limited will apply if you use the Holiday Lettings websites or housetrip.com, or if you use any of the Sites to make a booking enquiry or request in relation to a property that is advertised by an Owner contracting with Holiday Lettings Limited.
  * The _Privacy Policy_ of Guía de apartamentos Niumba S. L. U. ("Niumba") will apply if you use the Niumba website, or if you use any of the Sites to make a booking enquiry or request in relation to a property that is advertised by an Owner contracting with Niumba.

**FlipKey**

FlipKey.com **("FlipKey", "we", "our", "us")** is an online service through which users ("you") can plan vacation rentals and purchase travels. FlipKey believes in protecting your privacy.

Please review this Privacy Policy, which describes the types of personal data we collect from and about you when you visit our website (“Website” or “site”). This Privacy Policy also explains how we may use and disclose such information, as well as your ability to control certain uses of it.

We understand that making purchases and travel plans online involves a great deal of trust on your part and we respect your privacy. We take this trust very seriously, and make it our highest priority to ensure the security and confidentiality of the personal data you provide to us. Please read the following policy to learn about our privacy practices.

By accessing our site and using our services, you acknowledge that you have read and understood this Privacy Policy, as well as the practices for collecting and managing the information described herein.

This Privacy Policy was last updated on 25 May 2018. We may change this Privacy Policy at any time and we invite you to review it on a regular basis to keep informed of any updates.

  1. Collection of your personal
  2. How we use your personal data
  3. With whom we share your personal data
  4. How long we keep your personal data
  5. Cookies and other web technologies
  6. Your rights
  7. How we protect your personal data
  8. Children’s Privacy
  9. External links
  10. International Transfers
  11. Changes to this Privacy Policy
  12. How you can contact us

  1. **COLLECTION OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

Personal data means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified, such as your first and last name, telephone number, postal and electronic addresses, date of birth, password and payment information. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

In the course of our business, we collect and process personal data in different ways. We may collect personal data you give us directly but we also collect data by logging how you interact with our services, for example by using cookies on this website. We may also receive information from third parties.

The personal data we collect about you may include, but is not limited to: your name, email address, postal address, phone number, billing information, survey responses, reservation details and other information you may provide about yourself to our site, your IP address and web browser software. 

You can choose not to provide information to us, but in general some information about you is required in order for you to make a booking; participate in a survey, contest, or sweepstakes; ask us a question; or undertake other activities on the Website.

  * **Information that you provide us** : We receive and store any information you provide us on our Website or give us in any other way.
  * **Information from Other Sources** : We may obtain information about you from other independent third-party sources, including social networks that you use to connect with us.
  * **Combination of Information** : We may combine the information we receive from and about you, including information you provide to us and information we automatically collect through our Website, as well as information collected from other online sources or from third party sources.

**Information Automatically Collected** **:** We automatically collect some information about your computer or device when you visit the Website. For example, we may collect your IP address, navigation software used and the reference site. We may also collect information about your online activity and use of the Website, such as properties viewed, reservations sent, purchases made, the areas or pages of the Website that you visit, the amount of time you spend viewing or using the Website, the number of times you return to the Website, and other click-stream or site usage data. We automatically collect this type of information to try to better understand your interests and preferences of and to better personalize your experience.

  2. **HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We use the personal data that we collect about you only for specific purposes. This includes, but is not limited to offer our services to you, including your access to and use of our website and to publish your reviews, ratings and photos, communicate with you about your use of our site and services, to respond to, or follow up on, your comments and questions, and otherwise provide customer service, notify you about changes to our terms or privacy policy, ask you to leave a review or take a survey, operate and improve our site and services, personalize your experience on our site, measure interest in and improve our site and services, notify you about promotions and special offers, to let you partake in a prize draw, competition or complete a survey, protect, investigate and deter against fraudulent, unauthorized or illegal activity, administer and protect our business and to resolve disputes or troubleshoot problems.

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
  * With your consent.
  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.

**Marketing**

We want to make it easy for you to take advantage of travel-related opportunities on our Website. One way we do this is by sending you email messages that contain information about your travel-related interests. We believe these email messages will provide you with useful information about travel-related special offers available through our sites.

You will receive marketing messages from us if you have given your consent, if you have requested them, or if you purchased services from us and you have not opted out of receiving marketing messages.

Each time you receive an email of this type, you will be able to tell us if you no longer wish to receive them, or deny push notifications in the application, or change the settings of your mobile device to do so. You will be able to unsubscribe from marketing communications at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link that you will find at the bottom of each communication you receive from us.

Please note that we may continue to send you service communications, such as administrative, service or transactional messages related to one of your bookings. It is not possible to unsubscribe from these service communications.

  3. **WITH WHOM WE SHARE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

Any information you may disclose on our Website, in blogs, on message boards, in chat rooms, or on other public areas on the Website or other third-party websites that this Website may link to, becomes public information. Please exercise caution when disclosing personal data in these public areas.

FlipKey may share your information with other parties, including other group companies and third parties listed below. If we sell or divest our business or any part of it, and your personal data relates to such sold or divested part of our business, or if we merge with another business, we will share your personal data with the new owner of the business or our merger partner, respectively. If we are legally obliged to do so, we will share personal data to protect our customers, the site, as well as our company and our rights and property.

  * Suppliers including but not limited to property managers or owners, and third party providers of other services such as photography (if such services are made available from time to time, and you choose to avail of them).. Throughout the Website and its affiliated sites, all products and services provided by third-party suppliers are described as such. Please note that these suppliers also may contact you as necessary to obtain additional information about you or to facilitate travel reservations and bookings, or for other purposes consistent with the practices described in their privacy policies and terms of use.

  * Third-party vendors who provide services or functions on our behalf. This includes, but may not be limited to, credit card processing, business analytics, customer service, marketing, distribution of surveys or sweepstakes programs, and fraud prevention. These companies have access to personal data needed to perform their functions but are not permitted to share or use the personal datae for any other purpose.

  * Payment solution providers such as PayPal (if you use such payment solution providers), whereby you agree that we may share data about you with the payment solution provider and vice versa in order to facilitate or assess your use of the online payment platform or for other internal purposes. Such data may include details of enquiries, bookings, transactions, refunds, chargebacks or other claims or events relating to advertisements and/or payments.

  * Third-party vendors who provide services or functions on our behalf, including business analytics, payment processing, customer service, marketing, public relations, distribution of surveys or promotions, and fraud prevention. We may also authorise third-party vendors to collect information on our behalf, including, for example, as necessary to operate features of our Website or to facilitate the delivery of online advertising tailored to your interests. Third-party vendors have access to and may collect information only as needed to perform their functions and are not permitted to share or use the information for any other purpose.

  * Business partners with whom we may offer products or services in conjunction, or whose products or services we think may be of interest to you. You can tell when a third party is involved in a product or service you have requested because their name will appear with ours or separately. If you choose to access these optional services, we may share information about you, including your personal data, with those partners. Please note that we do not control the privacy practices of these third-party business partners.

  * Companies within our corporate family. We may share your personal data within the TripAdvisor Media Group, as well as with our parent companies and domestic and interenational corporate affiliate companies and websites. This sharing enables us to provide you with information about products and services (both travel-related and other) which we think might interest you, and to facilitate rental bookings. To the extent that our parent company and corporate affiliates have access to your personal data, they will follow practices that are at least as restrictive as the practices described in this Privacy Policy. They also will comply with applicable laws governing the transmission of promotional communications and, at a minimum, give you an opportunity in any commercial e-mail they send to choose not to receive such e-mail messages in the future.

We also may share your information if we believe, in our sole discretion, that such disclosure is necessary:

  * To comply with legitimate and enforceable subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process; to establish or exercise our legal rights; to defend against legal claims; or as otherwise required by law. In such cases we reserve the right to raise or waive any legal objection or right available to us.
  * To investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal or suspected illegal activities; to protect and defend the rights, property, or safety of FlipKey, our customers, or others; and in connection with our Owner and Traveler Terms of Use and other agreements.
  * In connection with a corporate transaction, such as a divestiture, merger, consolidation, or asset sale, or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy.

We also may share aggregate or anonymous information with third parties, including advertisers and investors. For example, we may tell our advertisers the number of visitors the Website receives or what are the most popular vacation destinations. This information does not contain any personal data and is used to develop content and services we hope you will find of interest.

**Your California Privacy Rights**

If you are a California resident, you may request information about our disclosure of personal data to third parties or affiliated companies for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact us at the address provided below in the “How you can contact us” section. You must put the statement “Your California Privacy Rights” in the subject field of your letter to us. We are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or that do not contain complete information. 

Non-affiliated third parties are independent from FlipKey and if you wish to receive information about your disclosure choices or stop communications from such third parties, you will need to contact those non-affiliated third parties directly.

  4. **HOW LONG WE KEEP YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure or your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

  5. **COOKIES AND OTHER WEB TECHNOLOGIES**

Cookies are small text files that are automatically placed on your computer or mobile device when you visit a website. Cookies contain basic information about your use of the internet. Your browser resends these cookies to our site each time you visit it so that your computer or mobile device is recognised in order to personalise and enhance your browsing experience.

We may use cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, log files, or other technologies to collect certain information about visitors to our Website and interactions with our emails and online advertisements, and to allow us to keep track of analytics and certain statistical information that enables us to improve the Website and provide you with more relevant content and advertising on the Website and other sites.

You can find out more detailed information in our Cookie Policy.

  6. **YOUR RIGHTS**

You can check, supplement and update the information you have provided to us or change your marketing preferences, by sending a request using our contact form: <https://helpcenter.flipkey.com/contact_form>.

In accordance with applicable law, you may also have the right of access, the right of rectification, the right to erasure, the right to restriction of processing, the right to data portability and the right to object. Please find below more details and information on how and when you can exercise your rights. We will respond to your request within one month, but have the right to extend this period with two months.

In accordance with applicable law, you may have the following rights with regard to your personal data:

  * The right to request access to your personal data. This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

  * The right to request to correct your data if they are inaccurate. You may also supplement any incomplete data we have, taking into account the purposes of the processing.

  * The right to request deletion of your personal data if:

    * your personal data is no longer necessary for the purposes for which we collected or processed them; or

    * you withdraw your consent if the processing of your personal data is based on consent and no other legal ground exists; or
    * you object to the processing of your personal data and we do not have an overriding legitimate ground for processing; or
    * your personal data is unlawfully processed; or
    * your personal data has to be deleted for compliance with a legal obligation.

  * The right to object to the processing of your personal data. We will comply with your request, unless we have a compelling overriding legitimate interest for processing or we need to continue processing your personal data to establish, exercise or defend a legal claim.
  * The right to restrict the processing of personal data, if:

    * the accuracy of your personal data is contested by you, for the period in which we have to verify the accuracy of the personal data; or
    * the processing is unlawful and you oppose the deletion of your personal data and requests restriction; or
    * we no longer need your personal data for the purposes of processing, but your personal data is required by you for legal claims; or
    * you have objected to the processing, for the period in which we have to verify overriding legitimate grounds.

  * The right to data portability. You may make a request to receive your personal data. You may also request that we send this personal data to a third party, where feasible. You only have this right if it regards personal data you have provided to us, the processing is based on consent or necessary for the performance of a contract between you and us or the processing is done by automated means.

You can exercise your rights by filing a request through our contact form: <https://helpcenter.flipkey.com/contact_form>.

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive.

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and verify your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

  7. **HOW WE PROTECT YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We want you to feel confident about using our services to plan and book your vacation rental, so we are committed to protecting the information we collect. While no website can guarantee security, we have implemented and maintain appropriate physical, administrative, technical, and organizational measures to protect the personal data you provide us against unauthorised or unlawful access, use or disclosure, and against accidental loss, damage, alteration or destruction.

For example, only authorized employees are permitted to access personal data, and they only may do so for permitted business functions.

  8. **CHILDREN'S** **PRIVACY**

Protecting children’s privacy is important to us. FlipKey does not direct the Website to, nor do we knowingly, collect any personal data from children under the age of 13. If we learn that a child under the age of 13 has provided personal data to the Website, we will use reasonable efforts to remove or delete such personal data from our files.

  9. **EXTERNAL LINKS**

Our Website may include links to third party websites, plug-ins and applications. If you access other websites from the links provided on our Website, the operators of those websites may collect information from you, which will be used by them in accordance with their Privacy Policy, which may differ from our Privacy Policy. We do not control these third-party websites and recommend that you examine the privacy statements posted on those other websites to understand their procedures for collecting, using, and disclosing personal data.

  10. **INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS**

Your personal data may be stored or transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. When we store or transfer your personal data outside the European Economic Area, we take the following precautions to ensure that your personal data is properly protected.

Whenever we store or transfer your personal data outside the European Economic Area, we will do so in accordance with applicable law and we will ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by implementing appropriate safeguards.Transfers of personal data are made:

  * to a country recognized by the European Commission as providing an adequate level of protection, or;
  * to a country which does not offer adequate protection but whose transfer has been governed by the standard contractual clauses of the European Commission or by implementing other appropriate cross-border transfer solutions to provide adequate protection.

By using our services, you understand that your personal data may be transferred to our facilities and those third parties with whom we share it as described in this Privacy Policy.

  11. **CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

FlipKey reserves the right to change, update and/or replace this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will note the date that revisions were last made to this Privacy Policy within the Privacy Policy, and any revisions will take effect upon posting. We will notify our users of any material changes to this Privacy Policy by sending a notification to the email address you have given us or by posting a notice on our site. We encourage you to check this Privacy Policy from time to time to review the most current version.

  12. **HOW YOU CAN CONTACT US**

If you have any questions or complaints about the processing of your personal data by us, please contact us using our contact form: <https://helpcenter.flipkey.com/contact_form>. You also have the right to lodge a complaint to the supervisory authority about the way we process your personal data. We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the supervisory authority, so please contact us in the first instance.

Our full details are:

FlipKey, Inc.  
Attn: Legal Department, Privacy Officer  
226 Causeway Street

Boston

MA 02114

USA 

In accordance with applicable law we have appointed a representative within the European Union. The contact details of our representative are:

Holiday Lettings Limited

Attn: Legal Department, Privacy Officer

7 Soho Square

London

W1D 3QB

If you contact us by phone, the conversations may be recorded. You will be notified of these recordings at the beginning of the call. We use these recordings to improve the quality or compliance of our customer service, to verify the accuracy of the information you provide, to ensure prevention of fraud and to train our teams. We keep these recordings for as long as necessary, and then erase them. Your personal data collected during a call is processed in accordance with the provisions of this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy is effective as of May 25, 2018.

This document sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. By using our website (“ **Website** ” or “ **site** ”), you indicate that you accept this Privacy Policy. Please do not use our site if you do not agree to this Privacy Policy.

Holiday Lettings Limited (" **we** ", " **us** ") is registered in England and Wales, Company registration number: 5282912. Our registered office is: 7 Soho Square, London, W1D 3QB, UK. We treat the personal data of site users with the utmost respect and confidentiality and take reasonable steps to ensure that your personal data is stored securely and accurately.

In general, we use the personal data we collect about you to help our advertisers provide accommodation solutions to users of our site, provide information services to relevant third parties, improve the features and services we offer and support our own marketing and promotion efforts.

By accessing our Website and utilising our services, you acknowledge that you have read and understood this Privacy Policy and the information collection and handling practices outlined in it.

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time so please check back regularly to keep informed of any updates. 

This Privacy Policy was last updated on May 25, 2018.

**Overview**

This Privacy Policy describes in detail our policy and practices regarding our collection, use and disclosure of your personal data.

We understand that providing information online involves a great deal of trust on your part. We take this trust very seriously, and make it a high priority to ensure the security and confidentiality of the personal data you provide to us when you visit our Website or use our services.

  1. Collection of your personal data
  2. How we use your personal data
  3. With whom we share your personal data
  4. How long we keep your personal data
  5. Cookies and other web technologies
  6. Your rights
  7. How we protect your personal data
  8. External links
  9. International transfers
  10. Changes to this Privacy Policy
  11. How you can contact us

  1. **Collection of your personal data**

Personal data means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified, such as your first and last name, telephone number, postal and electronic addresses, date of birth, password, and payment information. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

In the course of our business, we collect and process personal data in different ways. We may collect personal data you give us directly but we also collect data by logging how you interact with our services, for example by using cookies on this Website. We may also receive information from third parties.

The personal data we collect about you may include, but is not limited to: your name, email address, postal address, phone number, billing information, survey responses, reservation details and other information you may provide about yourself to our site, your IP address and web browser software. 

You can choose not to provide this personal data to us, but in general some personal data is required in order for you to receive relevant offerings from Holiday Lettings and its partners and enjoy other benefits of being a user of the Website; make rental property bookings; or participate in a survey, promotion or contest. In addition, some information is also required in order for you to ask us a question or initiate other transactions on our site.

  * **Information that you provide to us:** We receive and store any information you enter on our Website or give us in any other way.

  * **Automatic Collection of Information** : We automatically collect some information from your computer or device when you visit the Website. For example, we collect your session data, including your IP address, the navigation software used and the reference site. We may also collect information about your online activity, such as reviewed content, pages visited and reservations. We automatically collect this type of information to try to better understand your interests and preferences of and to better personalize your experience.

  2. **How we use your personal data**

We use the personal data that we collect about you only for specific purposes.

This includes, but is not limited to offer our services to you, including your access to and use of our website and to publish your reviews, ratings and photos, communicate with you about your account or use of our site and services, to respond to, or follow up on, your comments and questions, and otherwise provide customer service, notify you about changes to our terms or privacy policy, ask you to leave a review or take a survey, operate and improve our site and services, personalize your experience on our site, measure interest in and improve our site and services, notify you about promotions and special offers, to let you partake in a prize draw, competition or complete a survey, protect, investigate and deter against fraudulent, unauthorized or illegal activity, administer and protect our business and to resolve disputes or troubleshoot problems.

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
  * With your consent.
  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.

**Marketing**

We want to make it easy for you to take advantage of travel-related opportunities on our Website. One way we do this is by sending you email messages that contain information about your travel-related interests. We believe these email messages will provide you with useful information about travel-related special offers available through our sites

You will receive marketing messages from us if you have given your consent, if you have requested them, or if you purchased services from us and you have not opted out of receiving marketing messages.

Each time you receive an email of this type, you will be able to tell us if you no longer wish to receive them, or deny push notifications in the application, or change the settings of your mobile device to do so. You will be able to unsubscribe from marketing communications at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link that you will find at the bottom of each communication you receive from us.

Please note that we may continue to send you service communications, such as administrative messages about your account or transactional messages related to one of your reservations or your Holiday Lettings account. It is not possible to unsubscribe from these service communications.

  3. **With whom we share your personal data**

Holiday Lettings may share your information with other parties, including other group companies and third parties listed below. If we sell or divest our business or any part of it, and your personal data relates to such sold or divested part of our business, or if we merge with another business, we will share your personal data with the new owner of the business or our merger partner, respectively. If we are legally obliged to do so, we will share personal data to protect our customers, the site, as well as our company and our rights and property.

  * _Suppliers_ including but not limited to property managers or owners who fulfil travel reservations, and third party providers of other services such as photography (if such services are made available from time to time, and you choose to avail of them). Throughout the Website and its affiliated sites, all products and services provided by third-party suppliers are described as such. Please note that these suppliers also may contact you as necessary to obtain additional information about you or your travel plans, to facilitate travel reservations or bookings, or for other purposes consistent with the practices described in their privacy policies and terms of use.
  * _Payment solution providers_ (if you use such payment solution providers), whereby you agree that we may share data about you with the payment solution provider and vice versa in order to facilitate or assess your use of the online payment platform or for other internal purposes. Such data may include details of enquiries, bookings, transactions, refunds, chargebacks or other claims or events relating to advertisements and/or payments.
  * _Third-party vendors_ who provide services or functions on our behalf, including business analytics, payment processing, customer service, marketing, public relations, distribution of surveys or promotions, and fraud prevention. We may also authorise third-party vendors to collect information on our behalf, including, for example, as necessary to operate features of our Website or to facilitate the delivery of online advertising tailored to your interests. Third-party vendors have access to and may collect information only as needed to perform their functions and are not permitted to share or use the information for any other purpose.
  * _Business partners_ with whom we may offer products or services in conjunction, or whose products or services we think may be of interest to you. You can tell when a third party is involved in a product or service you have requested because their name will appear either with ours or separately. If you choose to access these optional services, we may share information about you, including your personal data, with those partners. Please note that we do not control the privacy practices of these third-party business partners.
  * _Companies within our corporate family._ We may share your personal data within the TripAdvisor group of companies, as well as with our parent companies and domestic and international corporate affiliate companies and websites. This sharing enables us to provide you with information about products and services (both travel-related and other) which we think might interest you, and to facilitate rental bookings. To the extent that our parent company and corporate affiliates have access to your personal data, they will follow practices that are at least as restrictive as the practices described in this Privacy Policy. They also will comply with applicable laws governing the transmission of promotional communications and, at a minimum, give you an opportunity in any commercial email they send to choose not to receive such email messages in the future.

We also may share your information if we believe, in our sole discretion, that such disclosure is necessary:

  * to comply with legitimate and enforceable subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process; to establish or exercise our legal rights; to defend against legal claims; or as otherwise required by law. In such cases we reserve the right to raise or waive any legal objection or right available to us.
  * to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal or suspected illegal activities; to protect and defend the rights, property, or safety of Holiday Lettings, our customers, or others; and in connection with our Owner and Traveller Terms of Use and other agreements.
  * In connection with a corporate transaction, such as a divestiture, merger, consolidation, or asset sale, or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy.

We also may share aggregate or anonymous information with third parties, including advertisers and investors. For example, we may tell our advertisers the number of visitors our Website receives or the most popular holiday destinations. This information does not contain any personal data and is used to develop content and services we hope you will find of interest.

  4. **How Long We Keep Your Personal Data**

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure or your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

  5. **Cookies and other web technologies**

We collect information via cookies and other similar technologies. Cookies are small text files that are automatically placed on your computer or mobile device when you visit a website. Cookies contain basic information about your use of the internet. Your browser resends these cookies to our site each time you visit it so that your computer or mobile device is recognised in order to personalise and enhance your browsing experience. 

Like many websites, we use "cookies" to enable us to personalise your visits to our site, simplify the signing-in procedure, keep track of your preferences and to track the usage of our Website.

You can find out more detailed information in our Cookie Policy.

Data collected to serve you with relevant advertising

Holiday Lettings is committed to providing you with relevant content and information across our sites. To do this, we may collect information about your travel-related searches and other site activities and use this information to serve you with ads on our sites or elsewhere online that match your interests. We may share this information with affiliated third parties so they can serve you with advertisements.

Data collected by business partners and ad networks to disseminate targeted advertisements

Many of the advertisements you see on the TripAdvisor family of sites are served by a company in the TripAdvisor group or one of its service providers. But we also allow third parties to collect information about your online activities through cookies and other technologies. The information gathered by these third parties is used to make predictions about your characteristics, interests or preferences and to display advertisements on our sites and across the Internet tailored to your interests.

  * Please note that we do not have access to or control over cookies or other technologies these third parties may use to collect information about your interests, and the information practices of these third parties are not covered by this Privacy Policy.

Your browser will have the option to prevent websites using cookies (your browser's help screen or manual will tell you how to do this), but please note that this may reduce the functionality of our site and other websites.

Like all websites, our servers automatically record "log files" containing information about the volume and characteristics of our Website traffic e.g. IP address, numbers of pages viewed, length of time spent on site. We use log files to build pictures of how our site is used, which help us to monitor and improve the service. We cannot identify you from your log files alone. 

  6. **Your rights**

You can check, supplement and update the information you have provided to us or change your marketing preferences, by sending a request to us using the Help Center or contact details provided below.

In accordance with applicable law, you also have the right of access, the right of rectification, the right to erasure, the right to restriction of processing, the right to data portability and the right to object. Please find below more details and information on how and when you can exercise your rights. We will respond to your request within one month, but have the right to extend this period with two months.

You have the following rights with regard to your personal data:

  * The right to request access to your personal data. This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

  * The right to request to correct your data if they are inaccurate. You may also supplement any incomplete data we have, taking into account the purposes of the processing.

  * The right to request deletion of your personal data if:

    * your personal data is no longer necessary for the purposes for which we collected or processed them; or

    * you withdraw your consent if the processing of your personal data is based on consent and no other legal ground exists; or
    * you object to the processing of your personal data and we do not have an overriding legitimate ground for processing; or
    * your personal data is unlawfully processed; or
    * your personal data has to be deleted for compliance with a legal obligation.

  * The right to object to the processing of your personal data. We will comply with your request, unless we have a compelling overriding legitimate interest for processing or we need to continue processing your personal data to establish, exercise or defend a legal claim.
  * The right to restrict the processing of personal data, if:

    * the accuracy of your personal data is contested by you, for the period in which we have to verify the accuracy of the personal data; or
    * the processing is unlawful and you oppose the deletion of your personal data and requests restriction; or
    * we no longer need your personal data for the purposes of processing, but your personal data is required by you for legal claims; or
    * you have objected to the processing, for the period in which we have to verify overriding legitimate grounds.

  * The right to data portability. You may make a request to us to receive your personal data that we record on our systems. You may also request that we send this personal data to a third party, where feasible. You only have this right if it regards personal data you have provided to us, the processing is based on consent or necessary for the performance of a contract between you and us or the processing is done by automated means.

You can exercise your rights by contacting us using the methods stipulated below.

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive.

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and verify your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

  7. **How  we protect your personal data**

We want you to feel confident about using the Website to plan and book your holiday rental, so we are committed to protecting the information we collect. While no website can guarantee security, we have implemented and maintain appropriate physical, administrative, technical, and organisational measures to protect the personal data you provide us against unauthorised or unlawful access, use or disclosure, and against accidental loss, damage, alteration or destruction.

For example, only authorised employees are permitted to access personal data, and they only may do so for permitted business functions.

  8. **External  links**

Our Website may include links to third party websites, plug-ins and applications. If you access other websites from the links provided on our Website, the operators of those websites may collect information from you, which will be used by them in accordance with their Privacy Policy, which may differ from our Privacy Policy. We do not control these third-party websites and recommend that you examine the privacy statements posted on those other websites to understand their procedures for collecting, using, and disclosing personal data.

  9. **International transfers**

Your personal data may be transferred to other countries for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. When we transfer your personal data outside the European Economic Area, we take the following precautions to ensure that your personal data is properly protected.

Whenever we store or transfer your personal data outside the European Economic Area, we will do so in accordance with applicable law and we will ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by implementing appropriate safeguards. Transfers of personal data are made:

  * to a country recognized by the European Commission as providing an adequate level of protection, or;
  * to a country which does not offer adequate protection but whose transfer has been governed by the standard contractual clauses of the European Commission or by implementing other appropriate cross-border transfer solutions to provide adequate protection.

By using our services, you understand that your information may be transferred to our facilities and those third parties with whom we share it as described in this Privacy Policy.

  10. **Changes to this Privacy Policy**

Holiday Lettings may change, update and/or replace this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will note the date that revisions were last made to this Privacy Policy on the first page of this Privacy Policy, and any revisions will take effect upon posting. We will notify our users of any material changes to this Privacy Policy by sending a notification to the email address you have given us or by posting a notice on our site. We encourage you to check this Privacy Policy from time to time to review the most current version.

  11. **How  you can contact us**

If you have any questions or complaints about the processing of your personal data by us, please contact us using our contact form: <https://help.holidaylettings.co.uk/contact_form>. You also have the right to lodge a complaint to the supervisory authority about the way we process your personal data. We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the supervisory authority, so please contact us in the first instance.

Our full details are:

Holiday Lettings Limited, 7 Soho Square, London, W1D 3QB, England.

Attn: Privacy/Legal Department

If you contact us by phone, the conversations may be recorded. You will be notified of these recordings at the beginning of the call. We use these recordings to improve the quality or compliance of our customer service, to verify the accuracy of the information you provide to ensure prevention of fraud and to train our teams. We keep these recordings for as long as necessary, and then erase them. Your personal data collected during a call is processed in accordance with the provisions of this Privacy Policy.

El presente documento sienta las bases que rigen el tratamiento que aplicamos a los datos personales que recopilamos o que usted nos facilita. Al utilizar nuestro sitio (“ **Sitio web** ” o “ **sitio** ”), usted indica que acepta esta política de privacidad. No utilice nuestro sitio si no está de acuerdo con esta política de privacidad.

Guía de apartamentos Niumba S. L. U. (" **nosotros** ", " **nos** ") está inscrita en el Registro Mercantil de Madrid, volumen 41.215, hoja B-321.334, folio 69, CIF B-64062953, y tenemos nuestra razón social en: Calle de Ausiàs March, 148-150. Planta 4-7, 08013 Barcelona, España. Estamos registrados en virtud de la Ley británica de protección de datos de 1998 (Data Protection Act 1998) con el número Z914623X. Tratamos los datos personales de los usuarios del sitio con el máximo respeto y confidencialidad y tomamos las medidas oportunas para garantizar que sus datos personales se almacenan correctamente y de forma segura.

En general, destinamos los datos personales que recopilamos sobre usted a ayudar a los anunciantes a ofrecer soluciones de alojamiento a los usuarios de nuestro sitio, a facilitar servicios de información a los terceros que corresponda, a mejorar las funciones y los servicios que prestamos, y a sustentar nuestros esfuerzos en marketing y promociones.

Al acceder a nuestro Sitio web y utilizar nuestros servicios, usted reconoce que ha leído y comprendido la presente Política de privacidad, así como las prácticas de recopilación y tratamiento de la información que se describen en ella.

Es posible que efectuemos cambios en la presente Política de privacidad de manera periódica; por ello, le recomendamos que la revise con regularidad para mantenerse informado de cualquier cambio.

Los últimos cambios de esta Política de privacidad se realizaron el 25 de mayo de 2018.

**Consideraciones generales**

La presente Política de privacidad describe detalladamente nuestra política y nuestras prácticas en relación con la recopilación, el uso y la divulgación de sus datos personales.

Entendemos que proporcionar información online implica un alto grado de confianza por su parte. Por ello, nos tomamos esta confianza muy en serio y es nuestra máxima prioridad garantizar la seguridad y la confidencialidad de los datos personales que nos proporciona cuando visita nuestro Sitio web o cuando utiliza nuestros servicios.

  1. Recopilación de sus datos personales
  2. Qué uso le damos a sus datos personales
  3. Con quién compartimos sus datos personales
  4. Durante cuánto tiempo conservamos sus datos personales
  5. Cookies y otras tecnologías web
  6. Sus derechos
  7. Cómo protegemos sus datos personales
  8. Enlaces externos
  9. Transferencias internacionales
  10. Cambios en la presente Política de privacidad
  11. Cómo ponerse en contacto con nosotros

  1. **Recopilación de sus datos personales**

Los datos personales hacen referencia a cualquier información sobre una persona que pueda llevar a identificarla, como su nombre y apellidos, su número de teléfono, su dirección postal y dirección de correo electrónico, su fecha de nacimiento, su contraseña y su información de pago. Esta información no incluye los datos resultantes cuando la identidad haya sido eliminada (datos anónimos).

Durante el transcurso de nuestras operaciones, recopilamos y tratamos los datos personales de diferentes formas. Podremos recopilar los datos personales que nos facilite directamente, pero también podremos recopilarlos haciendo un registro del uso que haga de nuestros servicios, como por ejemplo al usar cookies en el Sitio web. Asimismo, podremos recibir información de terceros.

Los datos personales que recopilemos podrán ser, entre otros: su nombre, su dirección de correo electrónico, su dirección postal, su número de teléfono, su información de facturación, sus respuestas a encuestas, los detalles de sus reservas y otros datos que pueda facilitar sobre su persona en nuestro sitio, su dirección IP y el software del navegador web. 

Usted puede elegir no facilitarnos estos datos personales, pero, en general, necesitamos algunos datos personales sobre usted para que pueda recibir ofertas relevantes de Niumba y sus socios, y disfrutar de otras ventajas de ser usuario del Sitio web, realizar reservas de alojamientos o participar en una encuesta, promoción o concurso. Además, también se requiere determinada información para que pueda plantearnos cuestiones o iniciar otras transacciones en nuestro sitio.

  * **Información que nos facilita:** Nosotros recibimos y almacenamos cualquier información que introduzca en nuestro Sitio web o que nos facilite de cualquier otra manera.

  * **Recopilación automática de información** : Recopilamos automáticamente cierta información de su ordenador o dispositivo cuando visita el Sitio web. Por ejemplo, recopilamos los datos de su sesión, como su dirección IP, el software del navegador utilizado y el sitio de referencia. También es posible que recopilemos información acerca de su actividad online, como el contenido consultado, las páginas visitadas y las reservas. Recopilamos este tipo de información de forma automática para intentar entender mejor sus intereses y preferencias y para ofrecerle una mejor experiencia personalizada.

  2. **Qué uso le damos a sus datos personales**

Usamos los datos personales que recopilamos sobre usted solo con fines específicos.

Entre dichos fines se incluyen los siguientes: ofrecerle nuestros servicios, como el acceso y uso de nuestro sitio web, la publicación de sus opiniones, puntuaciones y fotos; comunicarnos con usted en relación con su cuenta o el uso de nuestro sitio y servicios; responder a sus comentarios y preguntas o darles seguimiento, y, en caso necesario, ayudarle a través de nuestro servicio de atención al cliente; informarle de los cambios realizados en nuestras condiciones o nuestra política de privacidad; solicitarle que deje una opinión o participe en una encuesta, gestionar y mejorar nuestro sitio y servicios, personalizar su experiencia en nuestro sitio, medir su interés en nuestro sitio y servicios, así como mejorarlos; ponerle al corriente sobre promociones y ofertas especiales; permitirle participar en sorteos de premios o competiciones o completar una encuesta; establecer medidas de protección, investigación y disuasión frente a actividades fraudulentas, ilegales o no autorizadas; administrar y proteger nuestro negocio; y resolver disputas o solventar problemas.

Solo usaremos sus datos personales con arreglo a lo establecido en la ley. En la mayoría de los casos, utilizaremos sus datos personales en las siguientes circunstancias:

  * Cuando necesitemos ejecutar el contrato que acabe de firmar o haya firmado con nosotros.
  * Cuando sea necesario para la consecución de nuestros intereses legítimos (o los de un tercero), siempre que dichos intereses no contravengan sus intereses ni vulneren sus derechos fundamentales.
  * Cuando recibamos su consentimiento.
  * Cuando necesitemos cumplir con una obligación legal o normativa.

**Marketing**

Queremos que le resulte fácil aprovecharse de las oportunidades relacionadas con los viajes que se encuentran disponibles en nuestro Sitio web. Uno de los métodos que utilizamos para conseguirlo es el envío de mensajes de correo electrónico que contienen información sobre sus intereses relacionados con los viajes. Creemos que estos mensajes de correo electrónico le proporcionarán información útil sobre las ofertas especiales relacionadas con los viajes disponibles en nuestros sitios.

Le enviaremos mensajes promocionales si ha dado su consentimiento, si los ha solicitado o si ha adquirido nuestros servicios y no ha cancelado la suscripción para recibir mensajes promocionales.

Cada vez que recibe por correo electrónico un mensaje de esta clase, podrá indicarnos si no desea recibirlos más, o rechazar las notificaciones automáticas en la aplicación o modificar los ajustes de su dispositivo móvil con este fin. Podrá cancelar la suscripción para recibir comunicaciones promocionales en cualquier momento haciendo clic en el enlace de cancelación de la suscripción que encontrará al final de cada mensaje que le enviemos.

Tenga en cuenta que puede que le sigamos enviando comunicaciones de servicios, como mensajes administrativos acerca de su cuenta o sobre transacciones relacionadas con alguna de sus reservas o su cuenta de Niumba. No es posible darse de baja de estas comunicaciones de servicio.

  3. **Con quién compartimos sus datos personales**

Es posible que Niumba comparta su información con otras partes, como empresas de otros grupos y terceros que se detallan a continuación. Si vendemos o cedemos nuestra empresa o cualquier parte de ella, y sus datos personales los posee dicha parte vendida o cedida de nuestra empresa, o si nos fusionamos con otra empresa, haremos llegar sus datos personales al nuevo propietario de la empresa o al socio de la fusión respectivamente. Si estamos obligados por ley a hacerlo, compartiremos los datos personales para proteger a nuestros clientes y el sitio, así como nuestra empresa, nuestros derechos y nuestros bienes.

  * _Proveedores_ : entre los que se incluyen los gestores o propietarios de alojamientos que atiendan reservas de viajes y los proveedores externos que presten otros servicios, como por ejemplo, de fotografía (si dichos servicios están disponibles ocasionalmente y desea hacer uso de ellos). En el Sitio web y los sitios afiliados, todos los productos y servicios que prestados por terceros se describen como tales. Tenga en cuenta que también es posible que estos proveedores se pongan en contacto con usted, si es necesario, para obtener información adicional sobre usted o sus planes de viaje, para facilitarle las reservas de viajes o para otros fines de acuerdo con las prácticas que se describen en sus políticas de privacidad y sus condiciones de uso.
  * _Proveedores de soluciones de pago_ (si usted se vale de los servicios de tales proveedores de soluciones de pago): usted acepta que podamos compartir datos sobre usted con el proveedor de la solución de pago y viceversa con el fin de facilitar o de valorar su uso de la plataforma de pago online o para otros fines internos. Entre dichos datos podrán incluirse los detalles de las consultas, las reservas, las transacciones, los reembolsos o cualesquiera reclamaciones o hechos que tengan lugar en relación con los anuncios o los pagos.
  * _Terceros vendedores_ que proporcionen servicios o funciones en nuestro nombre, incluidos el análisis comercial, el procesamiento de pagos, el servicio de atención al cliente, el marketing, las relaciones públicas, la distribución de encuestas o de promociones, y la prevención de fraudes. También es posible que autoricemos a terceros vendedores para recopilar información en nuestro nombre, incluida, por ejemplo, la necesaria para utilizar las características de nuestro Sitio web o para facilitarle la entrega de publicidad en línea adaptada a sus intereses. Los proveedores terceros pueden recopilar y consultar únicamente la información necesaria para realizar sus funciones, pero no tienen permiso para compartirla ni utilizarla con ningún otro propósito.
  * _Socios comerciales_ con quienes podemos ofrecer productos o servicios, o cuyos productos o servicios creamos que pueden serle de interés. Puede saber si hay algún tercero está involucrado en un producto o servicio que haya solicitado porque su nombre aparecerá junto al nuestro o separado. Si elige acceder a estos servicios opcionales, es posible que compartamos con dichos socios información sobre usted, incluidos sus datos personales. Tenga en cuenta que no tenemos control sobre las prácticas de privacidad de estos socios empresariales terceros.
  * _Empresas de nuestra familia corporativa._ Es posible que compartamos sus datos personales con el grupo de empresas de TripAdvisor, así como con nuestras empresas matrices y nuestros sitios web y nuestras empresas afiliadas corporativas nacionales e internacionales. Este uso compartido nos permite proporcionarle información sobre productos y servicios, tanto relacionados con los viajes como de otro tipo, que puedan interesarle, así como facilitarle la reserva de alojamientos de alquiler. En la medida en que nuestra empresa matriz y nuestras empresas afiliadas corporativas tengan acceso a sus datos personales, seguirán unas prácticas al menos tan restrictivas como las prácticas descritas en la presente Política de privacidad. Asimismo, cumplirán con las leyes aplicables que rijan la transmisión de comunicaciones promocionales y, como mínimo, en todos los mensajes de correo electrónico comerciales que le envíen le ofrecerán la opción de elegir si desea dejar de recibir tales mensajes en el futuro.

También es posible que compartamos su información si consideramos, a nuestra entera discreción, que dicha divulgación es necesaria:

  * Para cumplir con citaciones, órdenes judiciales u otros procedimientos legales legítimos y exigibles; para establecer o ejercer nuestros derechos legales; para defendernos de demandas legales; o en otros casos en que la ley lo exija. En tales casos, nos reservamos el derecho de interponer cualquier objeción legal o ejercitar los derechos que nos correspondan, así como desistir de los mismos.
  * Para investigar, prevenir o tomar medidas con respecto a actividades ilegales o presuntamente ilegales; para proteger y defender los derechos, los bienes o la seguridad de Niumba, de nuestros clientes o de terceros; y en relación con nuestras Condiciones de uso para propietarios y viajeros, así como otros acuerdos.
  * En relación con una transacción corporativa, como una cesión, fusión, consolidación o venta de activos, o en el caso poco probable de bancarrota.

También es posible que compartamos información anónima o agregada con terceros, incluidos los anunciantes o inversores. Por ejemplo, podríamos revelar a nuestros anunciantes el número de visitantes que recibe nuestro sitio web o los destinos de vacaciones más populares. Esta información no contiene ningún dato personal y se utiliza para desarrollar contenido y servicios que esperamos que sean de su interés.

  4. **Durante cuánto tiempo conservamos sus datos personales**

Solo conservaremos sus datos personales el tiempo necesario para cumplir los fines por los que los hayamos recopilado, incluidos los fines para satisfacer cualquier requisito legal, contable y de presentación de informes.

Con el propósito de determinar el período de retención apropiado, tenemos en cuenta la cantidad, la naturaleza y el grado de confidencialidad de los datos personales, el riesgo potencial de daños originados por el uso o divulgación no autorizados de sus datos personales, los fines por los que tratemos dichos datos y si podemos alcanzar dichos fines mediante otros medios, así como las disposiciones legales vigentes.

  5. **Cookies y otras tecnologías web**

Recopilamos información a través del uso de cookies y otras tecnologías similares. Las cookies son pequeños archivos de texto que se guardan automáticamente en su ordenador o dispositivo móvil cuando visita un sitio web. Las cookies contienen información básica acerca de su uso de Internet. Su navegador reenvía esas cookies a nuestro sitio cada vez que lo visita de modo que se reconoce su ordenador o dispositivo móvil para personalizar y mejorar su experiencia de búsqueda. 

Al igual que otros sitios web, utilizamos “cookies” para personalizar sus visitas a nuestro sitio, simplificar el procedimiento de inicio de sesión y realizar el seguimiento de sus preferencias y del uso que haga de nuestro Sitio web.

Encontrará información más detallada en nuestra Política sobre cookies.

Datos recopilados para ofrecerle publicidad relevante

Niumba se compromete a proporcionarle contenido e información relevantes en nuestros sitios. Para ello, podremos recopilar información sobre las búsquedas relacionadas con viajes que usted realice, así como otras interacciones que realice en el sitio, y utilizar esa información para proporcionarle anuncios acordes con sus intereses en nuestros sitios o en otros espacios de Internet. Podremos compartir esta información con terceros afiliados para que puedan ofrecerle anuncios.

Datos recopilados por socios comerciales y redes publicitarias para divulgar publicidad pertinente

Muchos de los anuncios que ve en la familia de sitios de TripAdvisor los proporciona una empresa del grupo de TripAdvisor o uno de sus proveedores de servicios. Sin embargo, también permitimos que terceros recopilen información acerca de sus actividades en línea a través de cookies y otras tecnologías. La información que recogen estos terceros se utiliza para realizar predicciones sobre sus características, intereses o preferencias y para mostrar anuncios en nuestros sitios de internet ajustados a sus intereses.

  * Tenga en cuenta que nosotros no tenemos acceso a las cookies ni otras tecnologías que estos terceros puedan utilizar para recopilar información acerca de sus intereses, ni las controlamos, y que las prácticas de información de estos terceros no están cubiertas por la presente Política de privacidad.

En su navegador, se le ofrece la posibilidad de evitar que los sitios web utilicen cookies (en el manual del navegador o en la ayuda en pantalla encontrará cómo hacerlo), pero le rogamos que tenga en cuenta que, si lo hace, puede verse afectado el funcionamiento de nuestro sitio y de otros sitios web.

Al igual que ocurre con todos los sitios web, nuestros servidores guardan automáticamente “archivos de registro” que contienen información sobre el volumen y las características del tráfico de nuestro Sitio web como, por ejemplo, la dirección IP, el número de páginas visitadas y el tiempo empleado en el sitio. Nos valemos de los archivos de registro para hacernos una idea de cómo se utiliza nuestro sitio, lo que nos ayuda a supervisar y mejorar el servicio. No podemos identificarle únicamente a partir de sus archivos de registro.

  6. **Sus derechos**

Puede consultar, completar y cambiar la información que nos haya facilitado o cambiar sus preferencias de marketing, enviándonos una solicitud a través de la sección de ayuda o los datos de contacto que figuran más adelante.

De acuerdo con la ley aplicable, también cuenta con los derechos de acceso, rectificación, eliminación, restricción del tratamiento, portabilidad de los datos y oposición. Consulte más detalles a continuación para saber cómo y cuándo ejercer sus derechos. Responderemos a su solicitud en un plazo de un mes, pero podremos ejercer nuestro derecho a ampliarlo dos meses.

Tiene los siguientes derechos en relación con sus datos personales:

  * Derecho a solicitar acceso a sus datos personales. Este derecho le permite recibir una copia de los datos personales sobre usted que tengamos en nuestra posesión y comprobar que les estamos dando el tratamiento adecuado según lo dispuesto en la ley.

  * Derecho a solicitar la corrección de sus datos si no son correctos. También podrá completar cualquier información que tengamos de usted a la que le falten datos, teniendo en cuenta los fines de su tratamiento.

  * Derecho a solicitar la eliminación de sus datos personales si:

    * sus datos personales ya no sirven para los fines por los que los recopilamos o tratamos;

    * retira su consentimiento, en caso de que el tratamiento de sus datos personales se haya aprobado mediante consentimiento y no se aplique ningún otro fundamento legal;
    * se opone a que se traten sus datos personales y no prevalecen otros motivos legítimos para el tratamiento;
    * sus datos personales no se han tratado con arreglo a lo dispuesto en la ley; o
    * sus datos personales tienen que ser eliminados para cumplir con una disposición legal.

  * Derecho a oponerse al tratamiento de sus datos personales. Daremos el visto bueno a su solicitud, a menos que tengamos un interés legítimo de peso para el tratamiento de sus datos personales o necesitemos seguir dicho tratamiento para reconocer, ejercer o defender nuestros derechos frente a una demanda legal.
  * Derecho a restringir el tratamiento de sus datos personales si:

    * presenta una alegación por errores en sus datos personales durante el período en que tengamos que verificar que sus datos personales son correctos;
    * los datos no se han tratado con arreglo a lo dispuesto en la ley y se opone a la eliminación de sus datos personales y a la restricción de solicitudes;
    * dejamos de necesitar sus datos personales según los fines que determinen su tratamiento, pero solicita la obtención de sus datos personales mediante demanda legal; o
    * se ha opuesto al tratamiento durante el período en que tenemos que verificar si prevalecen otros motivos legítimos.

  * Derecho a transferir sus datos. Podrá enviarnos una solicitud para que le hagamos llegar los datos personales sobre usted que tengamos registrados en nuestros sistemas. Además, podrá solicitar que le enviemos sus datos personales a un tercero, siempre que sea viable. Solo podrá ejercer este derecho si guarda relación con los datos personales que nos ha facilitado, si el tratamiento se ha autorizado mediante su consentimiento o es necesario para el cumplimiento de lo estipulado en el contrato que hayamos firmado con usted, o si el tratamiento se realiza mediante medios automatizados.

Podrá ejercer sus derechos poniéndose en contacto con nosotros a través de la información de contacto que figura más adelante.

No tendrá que pagar ninguna cuota o tasa para acceder a sus datos personales (ni para ejercer el resto de sus derechos). No obstante, podremos cobrarle una tasa razonable si su solicitud es manifiestamente infundada, repetitiva o desmedida.

Podremos vernos en la necesidad de solicitarle información específica que nos ayude a confirmar su identidad y comprobar que tiene derecho a acceder a sus datos personales (o a ejercer el resto de sus derechos). Se trata de una medida de seguridad destinada a garantizar que sus datos personales no sean revelados a otra persona que no tenga derecho a recibirlos. Asimismo, podremos ponernos en contacto con usted para solicitarle más información relacionada con su solicitud para hacerle llegar nuestra respuesta con la mayor brevedad.

  7. **Cómo protegemos sus datos personales**

Queremos que sienta confianza cuando utilice el Sitio web para planificar y reservar su alquiler vacacional, por eso nos comprometemos a proteger la información que recopilemos. Aunque ningún sitio web puede garantizar su seguridad, hemos implementado y mantenemos medidas físicas, administrativas, técnicas y organizativas apropiadas para proteger los datos personales que nos proporciona frente al acceso no autorizado o ilegal y la revelación de información y contra pérdidas, daños, alteraciones o destrucciones accidentales.

Por ejemplo, solo los empleados autorizados podrán acceder a sus datos personales y solo podrán hacerlo para llevar a cabo funciones empresariales permitidas.

  8. **Enlaces externos**

Es posible que nuestro Sitio web incluya enlaces a sitios web, complementos y aplicaciones de terceros. Si accede a otros sitios web desde los enlaces que se proporcionan en nuestro Sitio web, es posible que los operadores de dichos sitios web recopilen información sobre usted y que la utilicen de acuerdo con su política de privacidad, que puede diferir de la nuestra. No controlamos los sitios web de terceros y le recomendamos que examine las declaraciones de privacidad publicadas en esos otros sitios web para conocer sus procedimientos a la hora de recopilar, utilizar y divulgar datos personales.

  9. **Transferencias internacionales**

Sus datos personales podrán transferirse a otros países para los fines descritos en esta Política de privacidad. Cuando transferimos sus datos personales al Espacio Económico Europeo, adoptamos las precauciones siguientes para garantizar que sus datos personales se protegen de forma adecuada.

Siempre que almacenemos o transfiramos sus datos personales fuera del Espacio Económico Europeo, lo haremos de conformidad con la ley vigente y nos aseguraremos de que recibe el mismo nivel de protección mediante la implantación de medidas de seguridad adecuadas. Las transferencias de datos personales se realizarán:

  * a países reconocidos por la Comisión Europea por proporcionar un nivel adecuado de protección;
  * A países que no ofrecen una protección adecuada pero cuyas transferencias se rigen por las cláusulas contractuales normalizadas de la Comisión Europea o por la adopción de otras soluciones de transferencias transfronterizas apropiadas para ofrecer un nivel de protección idóneo.

Al utilizar nuestros servicios, usted acepta que su información se pueda transferir a nuestras instalaciones y a las de aquellos terceros con los que la compartimos, tal como se describe en la presente Política de privacidad.

  10. **Cambios en la presente Política de privacidad**

Niumba podrá modificar, poner al día o reemplazar esta Política de privacidad de cuando en cuando. En la primera página de la presente Política de privacidad, indicaremos la fecha en la que se realizaron las últimas revisiones y todas las revisiones tendrán efecto inmediato después de su publicación. Notificaremos a nuestros usuarios todos los cambios importantes que se realicen en la presente Política de privacidad mediante el envío de una notificación a la dirección de correo electrónico que nos hayan proporcionado o mediante la publicación de un aviso en nuestro sitio. Le recomendamos que consulte la presente Política de privacidad periódicamente para revisar la última versión.

  11. **Cómo ponerse en contacto con nosotros**

Si tiene alguna pregunta o queja sobre el tratamiento que hacemos de sus datos personales, póngase en contacto con nosotros a través de nuestro formulario de contacto: <https://ayuda.niumba.com/contact_form>. Asimismo, tiene derecho a presentar una queja al organismo de control para informar de la forma en que tratamos sus datos personales. No obstante, le agradeceríamos que nos diese la oportunidad de tratar estas cuestiones con usted antes de acudir al organismo de control. Por ello, le rogamos que primero se ponga en contacto con nosotros.

Nuestros datos de contacto son los que siguen:

7 Soho Square, London, W1D 3QB, United Kingdom.

A la atención de: Responsable de privacidad o departamento jurídico

Si se pone en contacto con nosotros por teléfono, las conversaciones podrán ser grabadas. Se le informará de estas grabaciones al comienzo de la llamada. Usamos estas grabaciones para mejorar la calidad o el cumplimiento de nuestro servicio de atención al cliente, para comprobar la exactitud de la información que nos facilita, para garantizar la prevención del fraude y para formar a nuestros equipos. Conservamos estas grabaciones el tiempo que resulten necesarias y, después, las borramos. Todos los datos personales que nos proporcione durante la llamada se tratarán de acuerdo con las disposiciones de la presente Política de privacidad.

Last updated: August 8, 2018
